- Monica?
- Yes?
Have you seen a big, white envelope
I left on my desk?
No, Mr. Orlando, I haven't.
Thanks.
- Hello.
- Good afternoon.
Can I have some paper
and an envelope?
Sure, let me see.
Great.
♪ Your love is like yesterday's newspaper ♪
♪ No one wants to read it anymore ♪
♪ Sensational when it was published ♪
♪ In the morning ♪
♪ Reports are confirmed by midday ♪
♪ By afternoon ♪
♪ The story's forgotten ♪
♪ Your love is like yesterday's newspaper ♪
♪ Its headlines filled the front page ♪
♪ So you're known everywhere ♪
♪ I cut out your name and kept it ♪
♪ Pasting it into my album of oblivion ♪
♪ Your love is like yesterday's newspaper ♪
♪ And what's the point ♪
♪ Of reading yesterday's paper? ♪
♪ News that everyone knows ♪
♪ And which I don't want to read ♪
♪ You were good for nothing, baby ♪
♪ So I threw you in the trash ♪
♪ I had you, I loved you ♪
♪ I supported you ♪
♪ But I no longer love you ♪
♪ No longer love you ♪
- Good evening.
I reserved for "Orlando Onetto."
One second.
Yes, that's right. Table 41.
- Thanks.
- Follow me.
Thank you, Orlando.
- Thank you!
- I'll bring out some slices.
Thank you.
Thanks, love.
A musical cake and everything!
Here.
How formal.
"Valid for two trips to lguazu Falls."
- Orlando!
- It's no small thing.
It's one of the Natural Wonders
of the World.
Wow!
When do we go?
In 10 days.
In 10 days?
And why "valid for"?
It's a long story.
You haven't bought them yet?
Yes, I bought them, printed them out...
...and put them in an envelope.
And then?
I had them at the sauna.
And?
I don't remember
where the fuck I put them.
Poor, senile old man.
We'll have to ask the doorman for help.
Orlando?
- Orlando, what's wrong?
- I don't know.
"I don't know"?
I don't know what's wrong with me.
What the fuck is wrong?
Get up. Come on.
Honey.
What's wrong with you?
Lean against the wall. Here.
Look at me.
Here.
Do you have the keys?
No.
Wait here.
No, Diabla, stop that! Come here!
Diabla!
Orlando, honey!
- Let's go!
- I'm fine.
Talk to me, honey. Okay?
Talk to me!
Please!
Where are we going?
To the hospital, Orlando, where else?
Focus, okay?
Hurry.
What?
Hurry UP-
I will, honey.
Help me, please!
Easy, ma'am. We've got him.
You okay? What's your name?
Can you hear me?
Juan Pablo, hurry up!
Careful, careful!
One, two, three.
- What's your name? Can you hear me?
- His name is Orlando.
- What happened?
- I don't know!
- Is he on medication?
- No.
- How old is he?
- Fifty-seven.
Hurry up, he's not responding!
Did he feel sick?
He woke up with a headache
and was acting strange.
- When?
- Maybe 15 or 20 minutes ago.
Unconscious male patient, 57,
hemorrhage on the left side.
Frontal contusion.
Ready? One, two, three.
Graciela, call the doctor.
Pass the scissors.
- Watch his pulse.
- Careful of his shirt.
- Miss, you have to go.
- I brought him as fast as I could.
Please wait outside.
We'll take care of him.
Stay calm.
Go, go.
- Are you a family member?
- No, I brought him in.
- So you don't know him?
- Yes, we're friends.
These are his things.
They can't be in there.
How is he?
They'll let you know.
Just wait a bit.
- Good evening.
So are you a member
of Mr. Onetto's family?
Yes.
- Are you his partner?
- Yes, we're partners.
- Sorry, your name is...?
- Marina Vidal.
But that's a nickname?
Excuse me?
Could you come with me...
...to talk in private?
Is something wrong?
No, I'd like to talk to you.
- But is there a problem?
- No.
This way.
Orlando?
I'm Orlando's friend.
- With whom am I speaking?
- With Marina.
- I'm...
- Yes, I know who you are, ma'am
The thing is,
Orlando started feeling sick.
When?
About an hour and a half ago.
I brought him to the hospital, but...
Which hospital?
Saint Thomas.
Uh..hmm.
And he collapsed in the car.
Yes..
- And he died.
- He died?
Yes, just now.
The doctor says it was an aneurysm.
I'm very sorry.
Hallo?
Yes, I'm here.
- You haven't called anyone else, right?
- No, no one.
Fine.
But I need someone to come here.
I can't take care of this.
Ok. Don't worry. I'll tell the family.
Don't call anyone.
Ok!
Ok.
Miss Marina Vidal?
- Yes, what is it?
- Come with me, please.
Sergeant.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
You didn't have to treat me
like a criminal.
I'll leave you to your work.
Miss, I need your details.
- Here?
- Here.
Full name.
Marina.
Do you have your ID card?
It's still pending, sir.
Until it has changed,
this is still your legal name.
My name is Marina Vidal.
Do you have a problem with that?
Why did you run off?
- Why am I being detained?
- You're not being detained, sir.
So why do you have my ID card?
Evening.
Marina?
Thanks for everything.
Sorry you had to go through this.
I'm Gabe.
Hello, Gabo.
How are you?
- Hello.
- How are you?
Gabriel Onetto, brother of the deceased.
Is something wrong?
No, everything is fine.
He brought him and left in a hurry,
but we needed to speak to him.
You can speak to me.
I'm his family. I'll take care of this.
You must understand that the young lady
was with my brother when he died...
...so it's a sensitive situation.
Thank you.
Your telephone number, please.
Nine...
...814...
...95...
...75.
Marina! We need you here!
I'm coming!
- Everything all right?
- Yes, thank you.
- Excuse me, could I have some water?
- Yes.
You didn't want to come,
and I was calling you for the night shift.
Damn.
I couldn't check my phone, Alessandra.
The celebration was intense.
But you came. I appreciate that.
- Do you need anything?
- No. Everything's fine.
- You sure?
- Yes, I'm sure.
Always so mysterious.
It's been ringing for a while.
Thanks.
I'll be right back.
This is Sonia.
The wife... I mean...
Ex-wife of Orlando.
I know. How are you, ma'am?
First of ail,
there's no need to be so formal.
I talked to Gabo. He said you're living
in Orlando's apartment. Is that right?
Yes, it's true.
Well, I need his car.
Of course.
- You could've left it with Gabo.
- He didn't want it.
Ma'am, I mean, Sonia. Tell me
when you need it and I'll drop it off.
Let's see... Tomorrow.
Could you drop it off at my office?
I'll text you the address.
Leave it in the parking lot.
Just ask, and they'll tell you where.
Ok.
At 10:30? Is that okay?
I'll make it work.
Anything else of his that you have?
No.
Just personal things.
We'll have to work out
what to do with the apartment too.
Of course.
I want you to handle
all practical affairs with me.
Yes.
Can we talk about that when we meet?
I'm at work right now.
Hey... hey!
- Can you bring the check?
- Right away.
I'll be right back.
Marina, someone's here for you.
- Who?
- I don't know.
- Where?
- At the entrance.
Good afternoon, Marina.
Thanks for coming out.
It'll just be two minutes.
- Hello.
I'm Detective Adriana Cortés...
...from the Investigative Police's
Sexual Offenses Unit.
Good afternoon.
First, I want to offer my condolences.
They told me what happened.
I'm really sorry.
The fact that you ran away
from the hospital...
...really concerned me.
Could we talk there?
- Of course.
- Please.
I didn't run away.
There must be some mistake, then.
Could I see your ID, please?
One question:
Mr. Orlando...
- Onetto.
- Yes.
Was he paying you?
We were a couple.
So you cared for each other.
It wasn't just sexual.
It was a healthy, consensual relationship
between two adults.
Why do you ask?
He was old enough to be your father.
Did you consume drugs
before his seizure?
- No.
- Alcohol?
Yes.
Did you have sex?
I don't remember.
I need to know
if he suffered any physical stress.
Nothing unusual.
The thing is, Mr. Onetto's body...
...arrived with injuries, bruises.
He suffered blows to his arms,
sides and neck.
And had a contusion on his head.
The injuries were fresh.
I talked to the doctor about all of this.
Did you talk to his family?
Excuse me.
It's about the check for Table 15.
- I'll be right there.
- Five minutes, please.
- Can't they cover for you?
- No.
I need to get back, or they'll fire me.
Look, I've been working on
the streets for 23 years.
Fourteen years in Sexual Offenses,
and I have a master's degree in it.
I know very well what happens
to people-- Sorry, women like you.
I've seen everything.
Everything.
I want you to know
I understand and support you.
Did you have
to defend yourself from him?
- Am I being arrested?
- No.
- Then I'm going because--
- Wait, let's do this.
Call me when you're done,
so we can talk properly...
...and I can sleep well, all right?
Talk about what?
I'll be waiting for you.
It'll be best if you don't leave Santiago.
Okay, bye.
Bye, Marina. Thanks, nice place!
Thanks.
- Everything okay?
- Yeah.
- Did you notice I tried to save you?
- Yes, I did. Thanks.
Will you tell me
what the fuck's going on?
Some other time?
I've had a terrible day.
Sure.
Diabla.
Hey, you.
Marina, this is Detective Cortés.
You must have a good reason
to stand up an investigating officer.
Now, I won't ask.
Instead, I demand that you come in
and talk to me tomorrow.
I'll be at Forensic Medical Services.
Look for me when you get there.
See you at 12:30.
Don't call me. No excuses.
I'm not interested.
Please don't make me send someone
to pick you up.
Diabla.
Up, up!
Are you Marisa?
Marina.
I'm Bruno.
Sorry...
...I thought no one was here.
What happened, Marisa?
Your dad suddenly felt sick.
It all happened so fast.
What were you doing?
Sleeping-
That's all?
You were with him and he died?
Just like that?
We rushed to the hospital.
His body was bruised.
Why the fuck was his body bruised?
And his head injured.
He fell down the stairs
as we were going down.
That's why.
And those suitcases?
I was moving in.
Fuck.
What will we do with you, Diabla?
Orlando gave her to me.
- I'm sorry.
- He gave you Diabla?
Fucking hell.
Look...
...I slept next to Diabla...
...for years.
But I had to stop.
I didn't like the smell.
Did you know
there are two kinds of pet owners?
Those who have mammals
and those who prefer birds or reptiles.
We mammals have a neocortex...
...the most developed layer
of neural tissue...
...where emotions are generated.
That's where empathy...
...tenderness...
...and love are generated.
I don't see anyone with a lizard.
I don't get your analysis.
- What are you saying?
- I'm not saying anything.
Did you get the operation?
You don't ask that.
Why not?
I don't know what you are.
I'm the same as you.
Yeah, sure.
Can we talk another time?
Wait, wait, wait.
I just need to know
when you're leaving this apartment.
When I find something,
I'll let you all know.
- How much time are we talking?
- A few weeks.
No, not a few weeks.
Tell me a date, or I'll kick you out.
Know what? Get out of my house.
This isn't your house.
Incredible.
My dad was crazy.
If you steal anything, I'll know.
Hey, Bruno!
My name is Marina.
Bye.
Miss?
Hey, miss!
I'll pay for the wash.
You need a coffee.
Give me an Espresso.
How would you like it?
Double.
Idiot.
- Hi, good morning.
- Good morning.
I'm bringing this car to Sonia...
I don't know her last name.
Sonia Bunster.
She said to tell her when you arrived.
Please park on Level 4,
Parking Space 5.
She'll come and pick up the car.
- She wants me to wait down there?
- Yes, she said so.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome, go ahead.
Hello.
Hello, Sonia.
Oh, I'm sorry.
- Hello.
- How are you?
I've been wondering
how you look for about a year.
It's different face-to-face.
Of course.
As you can see, ma'am:
Flesh and bones.
Yes, it's just that...
...I can't imagine Orlando being with you.
That's all.
And don't call me "ma'am."
- Here are the car keys.
- Thanks.
The documents are in
the glove compartment.
- Okay. Excuse me.
- Yes.
Complicated.
Really complicated.
Total quantum physics.
I won't talk about
the apartment now, but...
Try to hand it over as soon
as you can, okay? Hand it over.
- That's it.
- Thanks.
Sonia, I'm really sorry about all of this.
What are you sorry about?
The entire soap opera,
or this episode in particular?
No, about how things turned out.
Yeah.
You know, when I married Orlando...
...I was 38.
And we were really normal. We were--
We had a normal life.
So when he...
...came and explained to me...
...I...
I thought...
Sorry if it's crude
and blunt of me to say this...
...but I really think
that this is just perversion.
Sorry, but...
When I look at you,
I don't know what I'm seeing.
A chimera, that's what I see.
A chimera.
Sorry.
There's no need to be sorry.
You're normal, ma'am.
You're fine, ma'am.
- Hello.
- Hello, Sonia.
- Hello, Pablo.
- How are you?
- Me, I'm fine. And you?
Fine, thanks.
Great.
Thanks.
- Bye.
You know my 7-year-old daughter will be
at the wake this afternoon?
Yes.
And I'd love to know where it'll be.
I know how to be discreet.
Don't even think about going.
I have the right
to say goodbye to him too.
Look, it's my problem now.
You already had a hard time.
Now the formalities are my part.
And I want to compensate you
for everything you've done.
Really, so you can relax.
You don't need to go anywhere
or do anything.
And we'll handle this in a civilized way,
so we're both satisfied.
I don't need your money, ma'am.
Did you call the police?
No.
Well, in any case, I apologize.
I'm just looking out
for my loved ones, that's all.
Orlando was a loved one to me.
Yes, but you won't go
to the funeral or wake.
Understood?
I don't know how to explain it.
What can I say?
Daniel, you are not going
to the funeral or anywhere else.
Please!
Let us mourn as a family,
like it's meant to be. Don't show up.
I'm asking you as a mother.
Remember, there's
an entire family devastated, in shock.
I'd give my life for my
daughter, if I had to.
Adriana, I want to apologize
for not calling--
- Detective Cortés.
- Detective.
I want to apologize for not calling
last night, but I was overwhelmed.
- I took sleeping pills.
- Don't worry about it.
Let's go.
This way, please.
- Will we see Orlando's body?
- No.
I booked a room.
If I'm late, I'll be in trouble.
What do you need?
Well, because you didn't call me...
...I went over our conversation yesterday.
The toxicology test came back positive
for alcohol.
And marijuana.
Where are we going?
We're giving you a physical examination.
No. No way.
It'll take five minutes.
It'll be superficial. Let's go, please.
- But you didn't tell me.
- Marina, I went to see you yesterday.
I was very concerned.
And you said you'd call me after work,
you promised.
And you stood me up, like I was crazy.
I'm sorry, it's just...
I took some pills and fell asleep.
And the marijuana--
I need to confirm
that you don't have any injuries.
- But I don't have any injuries.
- So there's no problem.
What?
Why are you doing this to me?
It's what's done.
It's called a “possible injury evaluation."
Well, I refuse.
Fine.
Then I'll ask the district attorney
to open a case...
...on the death of Mr. Onetto.
Look, if we find nothing, this ends here.
You go on with your life.
You decide.
I'll close this so you're comfortable.
Thanks for your help. You saved me.
We're even now, then.
You said his name is Daniel.
How should I treat him?
Don't call her Daniel.
Treat her like a woman.
Ask her what her name is.
But use her female name.
What did she do?
I don't know. That's why we're here.
Was it something complicated?
Right.
This way, please.
- What's your name?
- Marina.
Pretty name, Marina.
Stand there, please.
Thank you.
Here we are.
Marina, right? Marina.
Please, could you...
...uncover your upper body?
This'll be really quick, okay? Here I go.
That's it.
Now, please raise your right arm.
A bit higher.
There.
The same with the other arm.
Very good, Marina.
Were you attacked in any way?
Did you fall or anything like that?
No.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Well, now I'll ask you
to uncover your lower half.
- Could you leave us so that...?
- No.
Sorry.
Could you uncover your lower half?
Almost done, Marina.
Could you please raise
your right leg, Marina?
To the side? There.
Hello, Marina.
This is Gabo.
Sorry to bother you. Look...
We're going to cremate Orlando.
It's what he wanted.
To be clear, this is my own idea.
Sonia doesn't know yet.
I wanted to offer you...
Yes.
...a bit of his ashes.
Thank you, but no.
I just fee! you should have them. Really.
In exchange for not showing up?
I'd love for you to come.
- But--
- I'm eating right now.
Sorry, I didn't want to interrupt you.
Gabo, I'm hanging up.
Wait a second, we haven't agreed on--
- Thanks for seeing me.
- Come in.
Fucking gout.
I can't believe
even your illnesses are corny.
You look awful.
Without glasses,
you can't even see me.
You look...
...awful.
Have you come to hone your technique,
or hide from the world?
Both?
And vice versa?
Look, I don't mind
you coming too little and too late...
...or when you need
a little moral support.
But I'm your teacher. For singing.
Lyrics.
Not salsa, or merengue...
...but lyrics.
And you're not my psychologist.
And you're not my father.
No.
What did I come for, then?
To sing, I hope.
To look for some love, maybe?
You can't look for love.
No. Not Saint Francis again, please.
Saint Francis doesn't say:
"Give me love, give me peace...
...give me light,
give me this, give me that."
Saint Francis says:
"Make me an instrument of your love.
Make me a channel of your peace."
Why don't you sing for me instead?
Diabla?
Onetto Textiles, good afternoon.
I have a wreath for Mr. Orlando Onetto.
Could you tell me
where his wake is being held?
Take it easy, beautiful.
Okay.
- Is this all you're stealing?
- If you had a bigger car, I'd steal more.
What?
You two sisters are starting already?
You'll scare me to death.
No.
I'll survive.
I think we should call the police.
- What for?
- Because it's a crime. Trespassing.
No, I don't want any more police,
doctors, hospital gowns, uniforms.
I don't want anything.
Orlando's son just wants me
out of there fast.
That's not the point.
- It's no way to communicate.
- Oh, please, Mr. Contradictions.
"That's not the point"? Butt out.
Butt out? I've heard these stories
for nine years.
I'll leave your house
as soon as I can, okay?
No, it's not that.
Our house is your house, always.
Always, right?
Yes, always, obviously.
- Can I have one last favor?
- Another one?
- Cut it out.
- What?
Cut it out.
- Could you drop me off here?
- Why?
- I want my dog.
- What for?
It's a bad idea
for you to do anything alone.
No. Wait until we get home.
There, we can smoke something.
We can relax, and you can make
a more considered decision, okay?
Fine.
Get out!
- You get out!
- Fuck, I'm driving.
Right...
No one says a word!
Leave, please.
Mama...!
Get out, they said.
Have you no respect for people's pain?
Get out!
Marina!
I'm sorry!
I'm very sorry.
Everyone is upset.
It's not about you. I'm sorry.
Saying goodbye to a loved one when
he dies is a basic human right, isn't it?
Yes.
You're absolutely right.
It's done, Gabo.
Go back. Careful not to fall.
Why did you come
to mess with the family?
Everyone told you to leave us alone.
What do you want?
For you to get out of here,
fucking faggot. Got it?
- What are you looking at?
- You're looking at me.
- Are you threatening me, fudge packer?
- No.
Go destroy someone else's family,
you fucking monster!
Hey! You fucking faggot.
Stop the car!
Stop!
- Motherfucker!
- Let go, coward!
- Let go! What do you want?
- You drive.
Fucking cowards!
What do you want?
Go. go!
- Where's my dog?
- Shut up.
What did you do to my dog, coward?
That's not your house.
If you liked my dress,
you could've taken it, asshole.
This motherfucker wears dresses!
- Let go!
- Did you cut your dick off?
Shut your mouth, it smells like shit!
Think you're Julia Roberts, piece of shit?
You wear a dress
with football-player legs?
You have no right to touch me!
Think your dad would be proud of you?
He would slap you if he saw!
You shouldn't have sent the police!
- What police?
- Let go of me!
Let go of me!
I can't hear you!
- Now, talk, motherfucker!
- Son of a bitch!
Talk, you piece of shit!
I hope it's clear now.
Let's go.
Hello, Marina.
Hello, Gaston.
Here it is.
"Orlando Onetto Pertier."
What does it say?
"We announce the painful passing
of our husband...
...brother, father, partner, and friend...
...Orlando Onetto Pertier.
A funeral service will be held today at
4:30 P.M. at Parque de La Paz Cemetery.
315 Ejército Avenue, Santiago.
His wife, brother and children..."
- Could you pass the avocado?
- Wait, listen.
"It is with great sorrow
that we announce the painful passing...
...of Orlando Onetto Pertier.
Onetto Textiles employees."
What's the point? I don't get it.
I'm reading.
What for?
Don't go.
It would be masochism.
Define "masochism" for me.
Really.
People who like to suffer. Do you?
- What's that got to do with it?
- I don't like to suffer.
I'm reading to my sister--
Listen, cut it out. Really.
Stop.
I'm going nowhere.
I've turned the page.
Life goes on.
- Why tell me what to do?
- No...
What doesn't kill you
makes you stronger.
Stronger.
I have orangutan hands.
Nonsense.
Just a sec.
I have to adjust it.
Here you go, sir.
Just a minute.
I lose everything.
Maybe it's the old age.
Here. Keep the change.
What's wrong?
Sorry, where is that key from,
the one with the number?
From my sauna.
- Your sauna?
- Yes, my locker at a nearby sauna:
Finlandia.
Why?
It just caught my eye, sorry.
- Hello.
Is it mixed?
But the areas are separate?
Of course.
How much is it?
Here.
Thanks.
- Where are the lockers?
- That way.
Get out, sir, I have an emergency.
I have an emergency too.
Get out!
Take Alameda Street, please, sir.
Marina!
- What the fuck are you doing here?
- The ceremony is over, go home!
Could you leave us in peace?
Move, move! Crazy man! Get lost!
- Sonia, she's a woman.
- She's not a woman.
Move!
Move it, made-up faggot!
Move it, piece of shit!
You motherfucker.
- Crazy woman!
- Marina, don't do that!
I want!
My!
Dog!
Orlando's keys.
All right?
- Let's go, Bruno.
- Relax.
Go!
Excuse me, ma'am.
Was Orlando Onetto's funeral held here?
I don't know. I just clean here.
Might you know where he is?
No idea, ma'am.
Come in.
Thank you.
Bye, Diabla.
A FANTASTIC WOMAN
Subtitles Translated by:
Matthew Way